<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>
        BASIC blog full text feed    </title>
        <link href="log/readings/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    
        <link href="/"/>
    
        
    <updated>2011-11-16T12:07:36Z</updated>

    <id>/log/readings/atom.xml/</id>

            <entry>
            <title type="html">Uncopyright</title>
            <author><name>Fernando Paolo</name></author>
            <link href="/log/readings/2011/uncopyright.html"/>
            <updated>2011-05-14T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-05-14T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/log/readings/2011/uncopyright.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&#34;http://leobabauta.com/&#34;&gt;Leo&amp;nbsp;Babauta&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some might know, I&amp;#8217;m not a fan of copyright. In fact, I&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://mnmlist.com/uncopyright/&#34;&gt;uncopyrighted&lt;/a&gt; this &lt;a href=&#34;http://mnmlist.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and my other blog, &lt;a href=&#34;http://zenhabits.net/&#34;&gt;Zen Habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while uncopyright and minimalism might seem at first glance to be unrelated, I believe they both stem from the same&amp;nbsp;mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright stems from a protective mindset, one that believes the creator owns his work, and must protect that ownership in order to profit from said work. The creator will share his work with others, but only at a price, and anyone who takes without paying, or uses it as a basis for further creations, is&amp;nbsp;stealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s the copyright&amp;nbsp;mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uncopyright mindset is that of someone who gives without any guarantee of profit, who lets go of ownership and believes the world owns his creation. He hopes to contribute to the world in a small way, and if others benefit from this contribution, that&amp;#8217;s a good thing. And if others use his contribution to create something new and beautiful, that&amp;#8217;s a wonderful&amp;nbsp;thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uncopyright creator lets go of ownership, because to hold on to ownership hurts the world, and to try to protect that ownership leads to unnecessary&amp;nbsp;stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minimalist also eschews ownership, at least to some degree, and believes owning things doesn&amp;#8217;t make him happy. Doing things makes him happy. Helping others makes him happy. Creating makes him&amp;nbsp;happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is from this place that the minimalist embraces uncopyright, and in doing so gives to the world and hopes that the world will be better for it, at least in a tiny&amp;nbsp;measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; Leo&amp;nbsp;Babauta&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Amazonia</title>
            <author><name>Fernando Paolo</name></author>
            <link href="/log/readings/2010/amazonia.html"/>
            <updated>2010-11-11T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2010-11-11T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/log/readings/2010/amazonia.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cristovam_Buarque&#34;&gt;Cristovam&amp;nbsp;Buarque&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a recent discussion, in the United States, someone asked my opinion regarding the internationalization of the Amazon Region. The youngster asserted that he expected a response of a humanist and not of a&amp;nbsp;Brazilian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first time anyone had established the humanist viewpoint as the starting point for my response. In fact, as a Brazilian I would have responded simply against internationalization of the Amazon Region. Even if our governments have not given the attention that this treasure deserves, it is ours. I responded that, as a humanist, realizing the risk of environmental destruction that threatens the Amazon Region, I could imagine its internationalization, just as for everything else that is important to&amp;nbsp;humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Amazon Region, from a humanist&amp;#8217;s point of view, has to be internationalized, then we should internationalize the oil reserves of the entire world as well. Oil is just as important to the well being of humanity as the Amazon Region for our future. Nevertheless, the owners of oil reserves feel it is in their right to increase or decrease oil production and to raise or lower the price. The rich of the world, feel they have the right to burn this valuable possession of humanity. Similarly, the financial capital of the wealthy nations should be internationalized. If the Amazon Region is a natural reserve for every human being, then it could not be burned down by the decision of a landowner or a country. To burn down the Amazon Region is so tragic, as the unemployment provoked by the arbitrary decisions of world wide speculators. We cannot permit that the world&amp;#8217;s financial reserves serve to burn down entire nations according to the whims of&amp;nbsp;speculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the (internationalization of the) Amazon Region, I would like to see the internationalization of all the world&amp;#8217;s great museums. The Lourve cannot belong only to France. Each museum in the world is a guardian for the most beautiful works produced by the human genius. It cannot be permitted that these cultural possessions, as the natural posession of the Amazon Region, can be manipulated or be destroyed according to the whims of an owner or a country. Recently, a Japanese millionaire decided to have a painting of a grand master burried with him in the grave. This painting should have been&amp;nbsp;internationalized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of the meeting, in which this question came up, the United Nations convened the Forum of the Millennium and the presidents of several countries had difficulties in attending due to barriers (they faced) at the border. Therefore, I contend that New York, as the base of the United Nations, should be internationalized. At least Manhattan should belong to all of humanity. Similarly Paris, Venice, Rome, London, Rio de Janeiro, Brazilia, Recife, every city with its own beauty, its own history should belong to the whole&amp;nbsp;world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the United States wants to internationalize the Amazon Region, due to the risk of leaving it in Brazilian hands, then we should internationalize all the nuclear stockpiles of the United States. Particularly since they have already shown that they are capable of using these weapons, causing a destruction thousands of times greater than the sad fires taken place in the Brazilian forests.
During their debates, the current &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;U.S.&lt;/span&gt; presidential candidates have defended the idea of internationalizing the world forest reserves in exchange for the debt. We could begin to use this debt to guarantee the right of every child in the world to attend school. We could internationalize the children treating all of them, regardless of their birthplace, as a posession which deserves the care and attention of the entire world. Even more so than the Amazon Region. When the world leaders attend to the world΄s poor children as possessions of Humanity, they will no longer permit that these children work when they should be studying, that they die when they should be&amp;nbsp;living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a humanist I accept to defend the internationalization of the world. So long as the world treats me as a Brazilian, I will fight so that our Amazon Region will be ours. Only&amp;nbsp;ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; Cristovam&amp;nbsp;Buarque&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Religion</title>
            <author><name>Fernando Paolo</name></author>
            <link href="/log/readings/2010/religion.html"/>
            <updated>2010-11-09T10:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2010-11-09T10:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/log/readings/2010/religion.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Dirac&#34;&gt;Paul&amp;nbsp;Dirac&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot understand why we idle discussing religion. If we are honest - and scientists have to be - we must admit that religion is a jumble of false assertions, with no basis in reality. The very idea of God is a product of the human imagination. It is quite understandable why primitive people, who were so much more exposed to the overpowering forces of nature than we are today, should have personified these forces in fear and trembling. But nowadays, when we understand so many natural processes, we have no need for such solutions. I can&amp;#8217;t for the life of me see how the postulate of an Almighty God helps us in any way. What I do see is that this assumption leads to such unproductive questions as why God allows so much misery and injustice, the exploitation of the poor by the rich and all the other horrors He might have prevented. If religion is still being taught, it is by no means because its ideas still convince us, but simply because some of us want to keep the lower classes quiet. Quiet people are much easier to govern than clamorous and dissatisfied ones. They are also much easier to&amp;nbsp;exploit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religion is a kind of opium that allows a nation to lull itself into wishful dreams and so forget the injustices that are being perpetrated against the people. Hence the close alliance between those two great political forces, the State and the Church. Both need the illusion that a kindly God rewards - in heaven if not on earth - all those who have not risen up against injustice, who have done their duty quietly and uncomplainingly. That is precisely why the honest assertion that God is a mere product of the human imagination is branded as the worst of all mortal&amp;nbsp;sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; Paul&amp;nbsp;Dirac&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
    </feed>